Guide to the United Nations Oral History Project Interview Transcripts and Tapes
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
United Nations Oral History Project interview transcripts and tapes
1983-2005
MS 1703
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8.04
(254 boxes)
These interview tapes and transcripts were produced as part of United Nations Oral History Project sponsored by the Institution for Social and Policy Studies of Yale University to document significant events in the history of the United Nations and its operations. Interviewees include U.N. officials, ambassadors from various countries, and other participants in the events documented. Events and topics documented include the San Francisco conference, the founding of the U.N., its charter, the founding of Israel, Middle East wars, the Congo, Korea, the Cuban Missile Crisis, relief operations, secretaries-general, the Falklands/Malvinas war, Iraqi weapons inspections, and United Nations operations.
Yale University. Institution for Social and Policy Studies. United Nations Oral History Project
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Deposited by the Historical Sound Recordings Collection, Yale University Library, 1995; additional materials transferred from the Political Science Department, 1996, 1997, 2003, and 2007; transferred from International Security Studies, 2014.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Related Material
Additional interviews produced as part of an earlier project are listed in the finding aid and are available through the Dag Hammarskjöld Library at the United Nations (http://www.un.org/depts/dhl/), where they are cataloged individually in the library's online public access catalog.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale-United Nations Oral History Project conducted oral history interviews to preserve the recollections of those involved in international political developments in which the United Nations has played a role. The project is affiliated with the Institution for Social and Policy Studies and the Department of Political Science at Yale University. The project is a continuation of a previous study undertaken under the auspices of Yale University between 1989-1991. The earlier study focused on important developments in the early history of the U.N., while the current project is primarily concerned with Central America, Namibia, Cambodia, and the Iran/Iraq War and the experience of UNSCOM in Iraq. Interviews were recorded on audiocassette, transcribed, and sent to interviewees for editing. The interviews were conducted by James S. Sutterlin, Jean E. Krasno, and William Powell. In addition to copies of transcripts in Manuscripts and Archives, Sterling Memorial Library, Yale University, copies of these interviews (and additional interviews not deposited at Yale) are available to researchers at the Dag Hammarskjöld Library at the United Nations.
Scope and Contents
These interview tapes and transcripts were produced as part of United Nations Oral History Project sponsored by the Institution for Social and Policy Studies of Yale University to document significant events in the history of the United Nations and its operations. Interviewees include U.N. officials, ambassadors from various countries, and other participants in the events documented. Events and topics documented include the San Francisco conference, the founding of the U.N., its charter, the founding of Israel, Middle East wars, the Congo, Korea, the Cuban Missile Crisis, relief operations, secretaries-general, the Falklands/Malvinas war, Iraqi weapons inspections, and United Nations operations.
Diplomacy; Human rights; Humanitarian intervention; International relief; United Nations -- History
- Inventory
  - Transcripts
    - Abu-Odeh, Adnan, on Amman, Jordan, 1998 March 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ahmed, Rafeeudin, on Cambodia, two copies with slight variation, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ahmed, Rafeeudin, on Falklands/Malvinas War, 1990 October 19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ahtisaari, Martti, on Namibia, 1999 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Aimé, Jean-Claude, on Middle East, 1998 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Akashi, Yasushi, on Cambodia, 1997 October 31 and November 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Albin, Gustavo, on Central America, see Tello, Manuel (Box 10, Folder 154)
    - Annabi, Hedi, on Cambodia, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Annan, Kofi, on Iraqi Inspections, 2000 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Antonini, Blanca, on Central America, 1997 July 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Antonini, Blanca, on El Salvador, [available as tape only, no transcript], 1998 February
    - Apter, David, on The Congo, Ghana, 1991 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Aronson, Bernard, on Central America, 1997 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Arria, Diego, on Central America, 1997 September 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Astrom, Sverker, on Sweden, 1990 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Baca Vasquez, José Salvador; Baca Vasquez, Luis Felipe; and Baca Vasquez, Migdonia, on Nicaragua, 1997 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Baena Soares, Joáo Clemente, on Central America, 1997 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Banbury, Anthony, on Cambodia, 1998 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bancroft, Harding, on Korean War, 1990 December 17 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Beeley, Walter, on 1956 Sinai War, Congo Crisis, 1990 June 20 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bendaña, Alejandro, on Central America, 1997 July 29 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Bennett, Tapley, on founding of the United Nations, 1990 June 24 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Berendsen, Ian, on Congo Operation, 1990 May 4 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Berlin, Mike, on Javier Pérez de Cuéllar, Sir Brian Urquhart, Kurt Waldheim, and various U.N. Activities, 2005 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Biggs, David, on Cambodia, 1998 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Blix, Hans, on UNSCOM (United Nations Special Commission on Iraq), 2000 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Boothby, Derek, on UNSCOM, 1998 July 16 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Botha, Roelof (Pik), on South Africa, 2001 March 5 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Buchanan, Ewen, on UNSCOM, 2001 July 18 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Butler, Richard, on UNSCOM, 2001 July 25 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Cañas, Roberto, on Central America, 1997 June 19 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Chamorro, Violetta, on Central America, 1997 November 5 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Cleveland, Harlan, on The Congo, 1990 April 22 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Cleveland, Harlan, on election of Secretaries-General, Cuban Missile Crisis, 1990 April 22 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Costa-Mendez, Nicanor, on Falklands/Malvinas War, 1990 October 27 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Cristiani, Alfredo, on Central America, 1997 July 25 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Crocker, Chester, on Namibia, 1998 July 20 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Crossette, Barbara, on Kofi Annan, Boutros Boutros-Ghali, and Middle East, 2005 April 28 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Dayal, Virendra, on Middle East, 1998 February (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Dean, Jonathan, on Congo Operation, 1990 February 21 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - De Brito, Dantas, on Korean War, 1991 March 8 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - De Mello, Sergio Vieira, on Cambodia, 1998 May 5 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - De Soto, Alvaro, on Central America, 1996 April 9 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - De Thier, Jacques, on Congo Operation, 1991 March 6 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Dieye, Hawa Binta, on Namibia, 1998 June 23 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Duelfer, Charles, on UNSCOM, 2000 October 7 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Dumeni, Kleopas, on Namibia, 1999 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Eban, Abba, on founding of Israel, 1956 Suez War, attitudes of US presidents towards UN role in the Middle East, Kurt Waldheim, 1990 April 16 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Eckhard, Fred, on Namibia, 1999 February 16 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Eckhard, Fred, on Kofi Annan, Boutros Boutros-Ghali, the Iraq War, and U.N. reform, 2005 May 10 and June 7 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Ekéus, Rolf, on Iraqi weapons inspections, 1998 February 3 and 27 and 2000 April 28 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - El-Farra, Muhammad, on Amman, Jordan, 1998 March 13 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Eliasson, Jan, on Middle East, 1999 November 9, 2000 April 11 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Epstein, William, on the formation of the State of Israel, 1990 October 22-25 (Box 4, Folder 51A)
    - Escobar Galindo, David, on El Salvador, 1997 June 21 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Evans, Gareth, on Cambodia, 1997 December 10 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Eytan, Walter, on founding of Israel, 1990 June 20 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Fawzi, Ahmad, on Kofi Annan, the Bonn Accord, Lakhdar Brahimi, and Sérgio Vieira de Mello, 2005 September 23 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Fiallos, Mariano, on Central America, 1997 July 29 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Finkelstein, Lawrence, on founding of the United Nations, 1990 November 23 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Foa, Sylvana, on Kofi Annan and Boutros Boutros-Ghali, 2005 April 15 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Gallucci, Robert, on UNSCOM, 1998 February 3 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Garcia Robles, Alfonso, on Mexico, no corresponding tape, 1984 March 21 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Geingob, Hage, on Namibia, 1999 March 10 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Ghorbal, Ashraf, on Middle East, 1998 March 11 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Godley, G. McMurtrie, on Congo Operation, 1990 April 20 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Goksel, Timur, on UNIFIL (United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon), 1998 March 17 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Goodrich, Leland, on founding of the UN, no corresponding tape, 1985 September 16 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Gordenker, Leon, on the Korean War and the United Nations Information Organization, 2005 April 15 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Goulding, Marrack, on UN peacekeeping operations, 1998 June 30 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Green, James, on founding of the United Nations, no corresponding tape, 1986 April 21 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Gross, Ernest, on Korean War, 1990 April 12 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Guaccio, Aldo, on UNIFIL, 1998 March 18 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Gullion, Edmund, on Congo Operation, 1990 May 8 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Gurirab, Theo-Ben, on Namibia, 1999 November 3 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Guyer, Roberto, on Middle East, election of Secretaries-General, 1990 November 1 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Hamarneh, Mustafa, on Middle East, 1998 March 14 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Handel, Shafik, on Central America, 1997 June 19 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Hannay, Sir David, on UNSCOM, 2000 September 21 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Heinbecker, Paul, on the Cold War, the International Criminal Court, NATO, and the United Nations Security Council, 2004 November 8 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Hiss, Alger, on founding of the UN, 1990 February 13 and October 11 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Hottelet, Richard, on early United Nations leaders and activities, 2005 May 6 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Hyde, James Nevins, on Israel, Korea, Dag Hammarskjold, China, 1990 April 18 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Jarring, Gunnar, on Middle East, 1990 November 7 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Jebb, Gladwyn, on founding of the UN, no corresponding tape, 1983 June 21 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Johnson, Joseph, on founding of the UN, no corresponding tape, 1985 June 10 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Jonah, James, on 1973 Middle East War, 1990 August 21 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Kamal, Said, on Middle East, 1999 March 12 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Katjavivi, Peter, on Namibia, 1999 December 14 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Katjiuongua, Moses, on Namibia, 1999 March 9 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Kay, David, on Iraqi inspections, 2000 April 10 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Khadduri, Majid, on Middle East, two copies with slight variation, 1997 March 20 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Kidron, Mordecai, on The Suez War, The 1967 War, 1973 Middle East War, Israel, 1991 April 17 (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Kirkpatrick, Jeane, on election of Secretaries-General, Falklands/Malvinas War, 1990 November 13 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Kittani, Ismat, on Middle East, 1997 October 16 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Lall, Arthur, on The Suez Crisis, 1990 June 27 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Lavrov, Sergey, on UNSCOM, 2001 April 18 (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Legwaila, Legwaila Joseph, on Namibia, 1999 February 10 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - LePrette, Jacques, on election of Secretaries-General, 1973 Middle East War, France, 1991 April 8 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - Lind, Per, on Dag Hammarskjöld, 1990 November 7 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Linner, Sture, on Congo Operation, 1990 November 8 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - Liu, F. T., on Congo crisis, 1990 March 23 (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - Liu, F. T., on the Middle East wars, 1990 September 22 (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Logan, Donald, on 1956 Suez War, 1991 April 22 (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Lundquist, Oliver, on founding of the United Nations, 1990 April 19 (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - Lush, David, on Namibia, 1999 March 20 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - MacKenzie, A. R. K., on founding of the UN, no corresponding tape, 1985 May 31 (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - Maksoud, Clovis, on Middle East, 1997 August 11 (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - Martineau, Raymonde, on Namibia, 1998 July 7 (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - Martinez, Ana Gaudalupe, on El Salvador, 1997 June 21 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    - Mashler, William, on founding of Israel, Ralph Bunche, 1991 May 16 (Box 7, Folder 108)
    - McGhee, George, on The Congo crisis, 1990 May 9 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - McMahon, Gerry, on Middle East, 1998 July 3 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - McNamara, Dennis, on Cambodia, 1998 February 16 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Meeker, Leonard, on Korean War, founding of Israel, 1990 July 24 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Meguid, Ahmed Esmat Abdel, on Middle East, 1997 October 3 (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - Millard, Guy, on 1956 Suez crisis, 1991 April 20 (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - Montaño, Jorge, on El Salvador, 1999 October 1 (Box 7, Folder 115)
    - Mudge, Dirk, on Namibia, 2001 March 9 (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Murray, Geoffrey, on 1956 Suez War, 1991 January 10 (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - Myint-U, Thant, on Cambodia, 1998 July 1 (Box 8, Folder 118)
    - Nassif, Ramses, on Middle East, 1998 March 9 (Box 8, Folder 119)
    - Nassif, Ramses, on Dag Hammarskjöld, U Thant, and the early United Nations, 2005 April 15 (Box 8, Folder 120)
    - Nusseibeh, Hazem, on Amman, Jordan, 1998 March 14 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Ortega, Humberto, on Nicaragua, 1997 July 30 (Box 8, Folder 122)
    - Ortiz de Rozas, Carlos, on election of Secretaries-General, 1990 October 30 (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - Otunnu, Olara, on election of Secretaries-General, 1990 September 24 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Pachachi, Adnan, on Iran-Iraq War, 1998 July 2 (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - Parsons, Anthony, on Falklands/Malvinas War, election of Secretaries-General, 1991 April 19 (Box 8, Folder 126)
    - Pell, Claiborne, on founding of the United Nations, 1990 February 20 (Box 8, Folder 127)
    - Perez-Guerrero, Manuel, on founding of the UN, no corresponding tape, undated (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - Pettersen, Helmer, on Namibia, 1999 September 9 (Box 8, Folder 129)
    - Picco, Giandomenico, on Iran-Iraq War, 1998 October 7 (Box 8, Folder 130)
    - Pickering, Thomas, on UNSCOM, 2000 April 3 (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - Pineau, M. Christian, on 1956 Suez Crisis, 1991 April 8 (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - Plaza-Lasso, Galo, on founding of the UN, no corresponding tape, undated (Box 8, Folder 133)
    - Rafael, Gideon, on founding of Israel, Security Council Resolution 242, 1956 Suez War, 1991 April 17 (Box 8, Folder 134)
    - Rangel, Beatrice, on Central America, 1997 September 16 (Box 8, Folder 135)
    - Richardson, Elliot, on Central America, 1997 October 7 (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Rikhye, Indar Jit, on The Congo Crisis, 1990 March 26 (Box 9, Folder 137)
    - Ritter, Scott, on UNSCOM, 1998 October 27 (Box 9, Folder 138)
    - Ros, Enrique, on Falklands/Malvinas War, 1990 November 1 (Box 9, Folder 139)
    - Roschin, Alexei, on founding of the United Nations, 1990 May 25 (Box 9, Folder 140)
    - Rosenne, Shabtai, on founding of Israel, 1990 June 12 (Box 9, Folder 141)
    - Sáenz, Miguel, on El Salvador, 1997 June 20 (Box 9, Folder 142)
    - Samayoa, Salvador, on El Salvador, 1997 June 19 (Box 9, Folder 143)
    - Sanderson, John, on Cambodia, 1998 July 10 (Box 9, Folder 144)
    - Shejavali, Selma, on Namibia, 1999 March 20 (Box 9, Folder 145)
    - Sherry, George, on Congo Operation, 1990 July 12 (Box 9, Folder 146)
    - Shihabi, Samir, on Middle East, 1998 July 7 (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - Sills, Joe, on on Dag Hammarskjöld, U Thant, and the early United Nations, 2005 April 15 (Box 9, Folder 148)
    - Sisco, Joseph, on Cuban Missile Crisis, election of Secretaries-General, US relations with U Thant, Soviet Union, 1967 Middle East War, 1990 October 18 (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - Smidovich, Nikita, on Iraqi weapons inspections, 1999 February 3 (Box 9, Folder 150)
    - Sommerfelt, Soren Christian, on founding of the United Nations, 1997 October 7 (Box 10, Folder 151)
    - Steiner, Ismat, on Namibia, 1998 May 16 (Box 10, Folder 152)
    - Stephanides, Joseph, on Namibia, 1998 April 20 (Box 10, Folder 153)
    - Tello, Manuel and Gustavo Albin, on Central America, 1997 August 6 (Box 10, Folder 154)
    - Tjitendero, Mosé, on Namibia, 1999 March 10 (Box 10, Folder 155)
    - Tomeh, George, on Amman, Jordan, 1998 March 16 (Box 10, Folder 156)
    - Tueni, Ghassan, on Lebanon, Middle East, 1998 March 17-18 (Box 10, Folder 157)
    - Van Bellinghen, Jean Paul, on Congo Operation, 1991 March 4 (Box 10, Folder 158)
    - Vargas, Mauricio, on El Salvador, 1997 June 20 (Box 10, Folder 159)
    - Vendrell, Francesco, on Central America, 1996 April 18 (Box 10, Folder 160)
    - Verheul, Adriaan, on human rights, 1998 July 2 (Box 10, Folder 161)
    - Watson, Alexander, on Central America, 1997 October 10 (Box 10, Folder 162)
    - Williams, Michael, on Cambodia, 1998 July 7 (Box 10, Folder 163)
    - Wolterbeck, Cornelis, on Weapons of Mass Destruction, no corresponding tape, 2001 October 8 (Box 10, Folder 164)
    - Zamora, Ruben, on El Salvador, 1997 July 24 (Box 10, Folder 165)
    - Zelaya, Marina, on Nicaragua, 1997 July 28 (Box 10, Folder 166)
  - Tapes
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Abu-Odeh, Adnan, 2 (Box 11–12)
    - Ahmed, Rafeeudin, 2 (Box 13–14)
    - Ahtisaari, Martti, audiocassette (Box 15)
    - Aimé, Jean-Claude, audiocassette (Box 16)
    - Akashi, Yasushi, 3 (Box 17–19)
    - Albin, Gustavo (with Tello, Manuel), audiocassette (Box 222)
    - Annabi, Hedi, audiocassette (Box 20)
    - Annan, Kofi, audiocassette (Box 21)
    - Antonini, Blanca, on Central America, 3 (Box 22–24)
    - Antonini, Blanca, on El Salvador, audiocassette (Box 25)
    - Apter, David, audiocassette (Box 26)
    - Aronson, Bernard, audiocassette (Box 27)
    - Arria, Diego, 1 (Box 252)
    - Astrom, Sverker, audiocassette (Box 28)
    - Baca Vasquez, José Salvador; Baca Vasquez, Luis Felipe; Baca Vasquez, Migdonia, audiocassette (Box 29)
    - Baena Soares, Joáo Clemente, 2 (Box 30–31)
    - Banbury, Anthony, 2 (Box 32–33)
    - Bancroft, Harding, audiocassette (Box 34)
    - Beeley, Walter, audiocassette (Box 35)
    - Bendaña, Alejandro, 2 (Box 36–37)
    - Bennett, Tapley, audiocassette (Box 38)
    - Berendsen, Ian, audiocassette (Box 39)
    - Berlin, Mike (Box 239)
    - Biggs, David, audiocassette (Box 40)
    - Blix, Hans, audiocassette (Box 41)
    - Boothby, Derek, audiocassette (Box 42)
    - Botha, Roelof (Pik), 2 (Box 43–44)
      - Use copy, 2 audiocassettes (Box 43U–44U)
    - Buchanan, Ewen, 2 (Box 45–46)
    - Butler, Richard, 2 (Box 47–48)
    - Cañas, Roberto, audiocassette (Box 49)
    - Chamorro, Violetta, audiocassette (Box 50)
    - Cleveland, Harlan, 3 (Box 51–53)
    - Costa-Mendez, Nicanor, 3 (Box 54–56)
    - Cristiani, Alfredo, audiocassette (Box 57)
    - Crocker, Chester, 2 (Box 58–59)
    - Crossette, Barbara (Box 240)
    - Dayal, Virendra, 2 (Box 60–61)
    - Dean, Jonathan, 2 (Box 62–63)
    - De Brito, Dantas, 2 (Box 64–65)
    - De Mello, Sergio Vieira, 1 (Box 66)
      - Use copies, 2 (Box 66Ua–66Ub)
    - De Soto, Alvaro, audiocassette (Box 67)
    - De Thier, Jacques, audiocassette (Box 68)
    - Dieye, Hawa Binta, audiocassette (Box 69)
    - Duelfer, Charles, 2 (Box 70–71)
    - Dumeni, Kleopas, audiocassette (Box 72)
    - Eban, Abba, 2 (Box 73–74)
    - Eckhard, Fred (on Namibia), 1999 February 14; audiocassette (Box 75)
    - Eckhard, Fred (on Kofi Annan, Boutros-Ghali, the Iraq War, and UN reform) 3 audiocassettes, 2005 May-June (Box 241–243)
    - Ekéus, Rolf, 3 (Box 76–78)
    - El-Farra, Muhammad, 2 (Box 79–80)
    - Eliasson, Jan, audiocassette (Box 81)
    - Epstein, William, 3 (Box 82–84)
      - Use copy, 3 audiocassettes (Box 82U–84U)
    - Escobar Galindo, David, audiocassette (Box 85)
    - Evans, Gareth, 1 (Box 86)
      - Use copies, 2 (Box 86Ua–86Ub)
    - Eytan, Walter, 2 (Box 87–88)
    - Fawzi, Ahmad, 2 (Box 244–245)
    - Fiallos, Mariano, 2 (Box 89–90)
    - Finkelstein, Lawrence, 2 (Box 91–92)
    - Foa, Sylvana (Box 246)
    - Gallucci, Robert, audiocassette (Box 93)
    - Geingob, Hage, audiocassette (Box 94)
    - Ghorbal, Ashraf, audiocassette (Box 95)
    - Godley, G. McMurtrie, audiocassette (Box 96)
    - Goksel, Timur, audiocassette (Box 97)
    - Gordenker, Leon (Box 247)
    - Goulding, Marrack, 3 (Box 98–100)
    - Gross, Ernest, 3 (Box 101–103)
    - Guaccio, Aldo, audiocassette (Box 104)
    - Gullion, Edmund, 2 (Box 105–106)
    - Gurirab, Theo-Ben, audiocassette (Box 107)
    - Guyer, Roberto, audiocassette (Box 108)
    - Hamarneh, Mustafa, audiocassette (Box 109)
    - Handel, Shafik, audiocassette (Box 110)
    - Hannay, David, audiocassette (Box 111)
    - Heinbecker, Paul (Box 248)
    - Hiss, Alger, 3 (Box 112–114)
    - Hottelet, Richard (Box 249)
    - Hyde, James Nevins, 2 (Box 115–116)
    - Jarring, Gunnar, audiocassette (Box 117)
    - Jonah, James, 2 (Box 118–119)
    - Kamal, Said, audiocassette (Box 120)
    - Katjavivi, Peter, 2 (Box 121–122)
    - Katjiuongua, Moses, 2 (Box 123–124)
    - Kay, David, audiocassette (Box 125)
    - Khadduri, Majid, 2 (Box 126–127)
    - Kidron, Mordecai, 2 (Box 128–129)
    - Kirkpatrick, Jeane, audiocassette (Box 130)
    - Kittani, Ismat, 2 audiocassettes (Box 131–132)
    - Lall, Arthur, 2 audiocassettes (Box 133–134)
    - Lavrov, Sergey, audiocassette (Box 135)
    - Legwaila, Legwaila Joseph, 3 audiocassettes (Box 136–138)
    - Leprette, Jacques, audiocassette (Box 139)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 139U)
    - Lind, Per, audiocassette (Box 140)
    - Linner, Sture, 2 audiocassettes (Box 141–142)
    - Liu, F. T., 4 audiocassettes (Box 143–146)
    - Logan, Donald, 2 audiocassettes (Box 147–148)
    - Lundquist, Oliver, 2 audiocassettes (Box 149–150)
    - Lush, David, 2 audiocassettes (Box 151–152)
    - Maksoud, Clovis, audiocassette (Box 153)
    - Martineau, Raymonde, audiocassette (Box 154)
    - Martinez, Ana Guadalupe, audiocassette (Box 155)
    - Mashler, William, 3 audiocassettes (Box 156–158)
    - McGhee, George, audiocassette (Box 159)
    - McMahon, Gerry, 2 audiocassettes (Box 160–161)
    - McNamara, Dennis, audiocassette (Box 162)
    - Meeker, Leonard, 2 audiocassettes (Box 163–164)